Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Photographs 5929 P
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Photographs
1945-1965
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
National Union of Hospital and Nursing Home Employees (NUHHCE)
Local 1199 Drug and Hospital Union
5929 P
2.33 cubic feet
2.3 linear ft.
Photographs.
Clippings, photocopies and audio visual material.
6694312
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, July 27, 2012
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, April 18, 2019
Biographical / Historical
As a local of the Drug, Hospital, and Health Care Employees Union, Local 1199 was founded by Leon J. Davis in 1932, to organize pharmacists in New York City. Nonprofessional hospital employees were organized starting in 1958.
Because of the large number of Black and Puerto Rican workers it sparked the first post war Civil Rights Movement. May 8, 1959 marks the start of approximately 3500 hospital workers striking against seven large private hospitals in New York City, the strike lasted forty-six days.
Professional and technical workes were added to the union in 1963, the same year they won the right to collective bargaining under provisions of the state's labor relations act. The union was granted the right to represent workers across the state in 1965. Registered nurses became part of the union in 1973.
In 1998 the union became part of SEIU and membership went up significantly.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 6085 G: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project "Frederick Douglass and His Time" Posters 6089 G: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Posters 6084 G: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Women of Hope Poster Sets 6140: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project 6069: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Additional Files 6140 AV: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Audio Recordings 6169 AV: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Audio-Visual Materials 6169: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Files 6169 MB: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Memorabilia 6169 P: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Photographs 5929 AV: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Audio-Visual Materials 5929 MB: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Memorabilia 5929: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Records
Labor unions -- Health facilities -- United States; Bread and Roses Cultural Project; National Union of Hospital and Nursing Home Employees.; National Union of Hospital and Nursing Home Employees. Local 1199 Drug and Hospital Union (New York, N.Y.)
6694312
- Active photos (Box 18, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  2 photographs
- AFL-CIO Founding Convention (Box 18, Folder 2)
- Anniversary. Rally - May 8, 1963 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  12 photographs
- 1945 Awards (Box 18, Folder 4)
  negatives
- 1945 Awards (Box 18, Folder 5)
- Children's Camp (Box 18, Folder 6)
  13 photographs, negatives
- Baltimore (Box 18, Folder 7)
- Blood Bank (Box 18, Folder 8)
  15 photographs
- Boycott Schools (Box 18, Folder 9)
  21 photographs
- Bricklayer Drug Plan Photos (Box 18, Folder 10)
  5 photographs
- Categories & Drug Store Interiors (Box 18, Folder 11)
  22 photographs
- Children's Camp Program (Box 18, Folder 12)
  6 photographs
- Church of Master Meeting (Box 18, Folder 13)
  8 photographs
- Davis, Leon (Box 18, Folder 14)
- Classes (Box 18, Folder 15)
  18 photographs
- Classes (Box 18, Folder 16)
  14 photographs
- Classes - Cosmetics (Box 18, Folder 17)
- Classes: Spanish (Box 18, Folder 18)
- Contact Sheets & Negatives: 1199 Hospital News (Box 18, Folder 19)
- Credit Union Committees (Box 18, Folder 20)
  1 photograph
- Civil Rights (Box 18, Folder 21)
- Davis - Post - Illness (Box 18, Folder 22)
  3 photographs
- Deceased Members (Box 18, Folder 23)
  4 photographs
- Drug Contract Negotiations: 1963 (Box 18, Folder 24)
- Drug Members & News: September 1964 (Box 19, Folder 1)
- Drug News: June 1961 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  16 photographs
- Drug News: November 1963 -- Training Program (Box 19, Folder 3)
- Edwards, Gladys (Box 19, Folder 4)
- Elections (Union) (Box 19, Folder 5)
- 1199 - Emblem (Box 19, Folder 6)
- Epstein, Harry (Box 19, Folder 7)
  news clippings
- Eye Care (Box 19, Folder 8)
- Finances Union (Box 19, Folder 9)
- Grand Central Hospital (Box 19, Folder 10)
  7 photographs
- Guild Division (Box 19, Folder 11)
- Hiring Hall (Box 19, Folder 12)
- Hiroshima Victim - Peace: September 1961 (Box 19, Folder 13)
- Hospital News: Aug. 6, 1959 -- Vol I, no. 11 (Box 19, Folder 14)
- Hospital News: Aug. 27, 1959 -- Vol. I, no. 12 (Box 19, Folder 15)
- Hospital News: Oct. 8, 1959 -- Vol. I, no. 14 (Box 19, Folder 16)
- Hospital News: Oct. 22, 1959 -- Vol. I, no. 15 (Box 19, Folder 17)
- Hospital News: Nov. 5, 1959 -- Vol. I, no. 16 (Box 19, Folder 18)
- Hospital News: Dec. 3, 1959 -- Vol. I, no. 17 (Box 19, Folder 19)
- Hospital News: Dec. 17th, 1959 -- Vol. I, no. 18 (Box 19, Folder 20)
- Hospital News: Jan. 21, 1960 -- Vol. 2, no. 1 (Box 19, Folder 21)
- Hospital News: Feb. 25, 1960 -- vol. 2, no. 3 (Box 19, Folder 22)
- Hospital News: March 17, 1960 -- Vol. 2, no. 4 (Box 19, Folder 23)
  9 photographs
- Hospital News: April 14, 1960 -- Vol. 2, no. 5 (Box 19, Folder 24)
- Hospital News: May 5, 1960 -- Vol. 2, no. 6 (Box 19, Folder 25)
- Hospital News: 6/13/1960 -- Vol. 2, no. 7 (Box 19, Folder 26)
- Hospital News: 7/14/1960 -- Vol. 2, no. 8 (Box 19, Folder 27)
  13 photographs
- Hospital News: 9/15/1960 (Box 19, Folder 28)
- Hospital News: 10/15/1960 (Box 19, Folder 29)
- Hospital News: 11/15/1960 (Box 19, Folder 30)
- Hospital News: 12/15/1960 (Box 19, Folder 31)
- Hospital News 1961 (Box 19, Folder 32)
- Hospital News: June 1963 (Box 19, Folder 33)
  11 photographs
- Hospital News: July 1963 (Box 19, Folder 34)
- Hospital News: Aug. 1963 (Box 19, Folder 35)
  10 photographs
- Hospital News: Sept. 1963 (Box 19, Folder 36)
- Hospital News: 1963 (Box 19, Folder 37)
  26 photographs
- Hospital News: 1963 (Box 19, Folder 38)
- Hospital News: April 1964 (Box 19, Folder 39)
  19 photographs
- Hospital News: Jan. 1965 (Box 19, Folder 40)
- Miscellaneous Hospital News (Box 19, Folder 41)
- Hospital News Unused Photos (Box 19, Folder 42)
- Installations: 1964 (Box 19, Folder 43)
- Installations: 1964 (Box 19, Folder 44)
- Karp, Tony (Box 19, Folder 45)
- King, Martin Luther (Box 19, Folder 46)
- Labor Day (Box 20, Folder 1)
  25 photographs
- Labor Day: 1959 (Box 20, Folder 2)
- Labor Day: 1959 (Box 20, Folder 3)
- Latin America Fiesta (Box 20, Folder 4)
- Magazine: 1199 News (Box 20, Folder 5)
- Manhattan Center: Malley Photographs (Box 20, Folder 6)
- Marshall, Thurgood (Box 20, Folder 7)
- Membership Meetings (Box 20, Folder 8)
- Conference Photos (Box 20, Folder 9)
- Members Miscellaneous (Box 20, Folder 10)
- Miscellaneous (Box 20, Folder 11)
- Negatives (Box 20, Folder 12)
  3 photographs; folder heading only mentions the negatives, but 3 photographs were found mixed in
- Negotiations (Box 20, Folder 13)
- Negro Rights (Box 20, Folder 14)
  17 photographs
- Organizing (Box 20, Folder 15)
- Pharmacy Comm. (Box 20, Folder 16)
- Negro Week Performers: 1954-1956 (Box 20, Folder 17)
- Negro Week Performers: 1954-1956 (Box 20, Folder 18)
- Negro Week Performers: 1954-1956 (Box 20, Folder 19)
- Picketing (1960's)? (Box 20, Folder 20)
  23 photographs
- Picketing (1960's) ? (Box 20, Folder 21)
- Political Action (Box 20, Folder 22)
  24 photographs
- Powell Committee on Local 144 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  2 photographs; news clippings with photographs
- Proofs; Negatives (Box 21, Folder 2)
- Rallies (Box 21, Folder 3)
- Rent Strikes (Box 21, Folder 4)
- Rivera Case (Box 21, Folder 5)
- Rockefeller, Nelson (Box 21, Folder 6)
- Roosevelt Years (Box 21, Folder 7)
- Salute to Freedom Year? (Box 21, Folder 8)
- Schools (Box 21, Folder 9)
- Sephardic Home Demo (Box 21, Folder 10)
- Spanish Material (Box 21, Folder 11)
- Sports-Recreation (Box 21, Folder 12)
- Stewards (Box 21, Folder 13)
- Strikes (Box 21, Folder 14)
- Tauber, Joseph (Box 21, Folder 15)
- Teen Time (Box 21, Folder 16)
- Toscanini (Box 21, Folder 17)
- Training Program: Drug (Box 21, Folder 18)
  24 Photographs
- Upstate NY (Box 21, Folder 19)
- WARO: Local 1199 (Box 21, Folder 20)
- West Virginia (Box 21, Folder 21)
- Workers - Head & Shoulder Shots (Box 21, Folder 22)
- World War - War Effort & Union Activities (Box 21, Folder 23)
- X-Mas (Box 21, Folder 24)
- Unidentified Hospital News: 1199 (Box 21, Folder 25)
- Unidentified Miscellaneous (Box 21, Folder 26)
- Unidentified Miscellaneous (Box 21, Folder 27)
- Unidentified Miscellaneous (Box 22, Folder 1)
- Unidentified Miscellaneous (Box 22, Folder 2)
- Unidentified Miscellaneous (Box 22, Folder 3)
  16 photographs -- (bent and curled)
- Unidentified Miscellaneous (Box 22, Folder 4)
  18 photographs -- (bent and curled)
- Unidentified Miscellaneous (Box 22, Folder 5)
- Unidentified Miscellaneous (Box 22, Folder 6)
- Unidentified Miscellaneous (Box 22, Folder 7)
- Unidentified Miscellaneous (Box 22, Folder 8)
- Images digitized from the collection. (Box 23)